# MARKO HENRIK HAUTALA

## Full stack Software Developer

github.com/markohautala / linkedin.com/in/markohautala
Stockholm, Sweden / markohautala@live.se / 072-291-07-50



#### **Executive Summary**

My name is Marko, and I'm a passionate and educated Full Stack Developer with a strong focus on frontend development. I code daily and have extensive experience in JavaScript, React, Django, Next.js, databases, HTML/CSS, REST APIs, Node.js, AI/ML and with AWS. I'm committed to creating user-friendly interfaces and well-documented, clean frontends and backends, all built with modern coding principles. My strengths include attention to detail, strong analytical skills, and quick problem-solving.

With over 9 years of experience, including three years as a team leader, I thrive in both independent and team settings. I'm eager to learn, grow, and bring my skills to a new, collaborative environment. I'm now looking forward to my next role as a full stack developer.

#### **Technical Skill Set**

Client-side	Server-side	Development & operations
HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, Tailwind, Next.js, Three.js	Python, SQL/NoSQL-databases, Django & Django-REST, Flask, Jinja, MongoDB, JSON, TypeScript	Agile, Jest-testing, CI/CD, Git, GitHub, Heroku, API:s, DevTools, Figma, VSCode, GitHub Copilot, Vercel, OpenAI, Azure, AWS

### **Portfolio Projects**

- 1. **HouseGram** A social media application for sharing dream-houses. Built with Django REST API as backend and React as frontend.
  - **Tech used:** Django REST API, React, Postgres, Cloudinary, Heroku, CSS/HTML. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/django-rest-api
- 2. **Nextjs OpenAI API Chat-app** AI/Chat-GPT like app for coders. **Tech used**: Next.js, AI, TypeScript, Tailwind, JavaScript, Vercel, API:s, OpenAI. Link: <a href="https://github.com/markohautala/nextjs-tailwind-ai-chat/tree/master">https://github.com/markohautala/nextjs-tailwind-ai-chat/tree/master</a>
- 3. **Django Auth and CRUD todo-app** Todo App with full CRUD-functionality and user Authentication. **Tech used**: Python / Django framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL-database, Heroku. Link: <a href="https://github.com/markohautala/django-auth-crud-app">https://github.com/markohautala/django-auth-crud-app</a>
- 4. **React to-do app with background animation** To-do application built and based on React. **Tech used**: React, JavaScript, Vite, Three.js, Heroku, HTML, CSS. Link: <a href="https://github.com/markohautala/react-app">https://github.com/markohautala/react-app</a>
- 5. **Bootstrap Online Resume** Online resume built with Bootstrap. **Tech Used:** HTML, CSS, API:s, Bootstrap, emailJS, JavaScript. Link: https://markohautala.github.io/bootstrap-online-resume/

#### Education

Jun 2023 - Aug 2024 Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote Based Learning)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development Advanced front-end specialization. 30 ECTS.
(Accredited by the University West of Scotland).

Sept 2018 - Jun 2021 Stockholm University & Stockholm, Sweden
The Swedish School of Sport and Health Sciences

Physical education (PE) teacher. 180 ECTS.

#### **Work Experience**

Fornuddens school - Tyresö, Stockholm

Physical Education (PE) teacher & team-leader

Aug. 2021 - Present

- **Active Listening and Communication:** I engage in daily communication and collaboration with various school stakeholders, enhancing effective teamwork and understanding of different needs.
- **Stress Management and Time Management:** I handle teaching responsibilities, administrative tasks, and documentation under tight deadlines, demonstrating stress and time management skills.
- **Decision Making and Problem Solving:** Teamleader over six colleagues, making quick decisions and solving unexpected issues efficiently, showing strong leadership and critical thinking abilities.
- **Organization and Adaptability:** I initiate and manage projects to improve work routines, displaying organizational skills, multitasking ability, and adaptability to new challenges.

Kaffeknappen AB - Stockholm, Sweden

Service & Customer Relations Manager

June 2016 - June 2018

- **High responsibility:** Managed and had full responsibility over exclusive coffee machines for 100 large companies in Södermalm, maintaining high service standards. All customers were very satisfied.
- **Problem-solving and adaptability:** I retained Kaffeknappen's largest corporate client by resolving previous dissatisfaction, earning positive feedback (see reference).
- **Time management and self-motivation:** I showed strong independence, responsibility, and efficiency in meeting deadlines.

## **Certificates/Collaborative Projects**

- AI foundations Machine Learning
- **Hackathon** (agile collaboration with six team members) built a website to calculate investment profitability using NPV.

https://eu.badgr.com/public/assertions/ZRUiU4Q2R52vnJjw8SbO5w?identity\_email=markohautala@live.se

#### Additional Information/Interests

- Listening continuously to tech podcasts like "Developers!" and "HTML All the things" to stay updated with the software/IT-industry. I also regularly engage in coding communities like the Slack tech forum.
- Strong interest in different Al-technologies.
- Coding on personal portfolio projects every day.
- High interests in self-improvement, fitness, food and nutrition.
- I both speak, read and write fluently in Swedish, English and Finnish.

#### References

## Kaffeknappen AB

"Regarding Marko, I cannot praise him enough. He provides fantastic service and maintains a very professional attitude with customers. He is an incredibly important ambassador for the company Kaffeknappen. It is rare to see such a young man take on such comprehensive responsibility towards customers.

Best regards,

A very satisfied customer (DN - Dagens Nyheter)."

More references available on request.